A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), Office Files of Virginia Davis Floyd FA513
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH), Office Files of Virginia Davis Floyd
1973-2002 (Bulk 1994-2002)
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA513
5 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access note
Retrieval Requests:
All requests to view this collection are to be made by Box Number. Retrieval of individual folders is not permitted.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Publications and Reports, 1973-2001; I
  - Background Papers, Jun 1973 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Publications and Working Papers, 1986-1992 (Box 1)
  - The Changing Context for Movements to Improve Women's Lives, Sep 29, 1986 (Box 1)
  - The AIDS Challenge -- A Ford Foundation Response, Dec 1987 (Box 1)
  - Reproductive Health Papers, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - Reproductive Health -- A Strategy for the 1990s, Jun 1991 (Box 1)
  - Reproductive Health in Indonesia -- A Program Paper, Sep 20, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Violence Against Women -- Addressing a Global Problem, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Program Strategies in Reproductive Health and Population -- Bangladesh, Jan 1992 (Box 1)
  - Reproductive Health/Reproductive Rights -- Legal, Policy and Ethical Issues, Jan 1992 (Box 1)
  - Project on Ethics and Reproductive Health -- Visit to the Philippines, Sep 28, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Trip Report -- Mexico, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Report on Visit to China, Feb 1993 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Reproductive Health and Population Program Meeting Notes, Apr 27-30, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Ruth Macklin -- Trip Reports (Peru, Colombia, Nigeria), 1994 (Box 1)
  - The World's Rural Poor and How to Assist Them, Sep 1994 (Box 1)
  - Strengthening Fragile Families -- A Proposed Strategy for the Ford Foundation, Nov 1994 (Box 1)
  - The Ford Foundation's Neighborhood and Family Initiative -- Interim Report, Sep 1995 (Box 1)
  - Girls Education and Sexuality -- A Working Paper, Feb 14, 1996 (Box 1)
  - The Ford Foundation's Reproductive Health and Population Program -- A Five Year Review (Box 1)
  - The Ford Foundation in Bangladesh, [1997] (Box 1)
  - Strengthening Fragile Families Initiative Report 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Strengthening Fragile Families Initiative Media and Publications, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Reproductive Health Affinity Group -- Reports/Materials, 1998-2001 (Box 1)
  - Reproductive Health Review Meeting, May 1998 (Box 1)
  - Human Development and Reproductive Health Program Review, Sep 15, 1998 (Box 1)
  - The Asset Building Framework -- Perspectives and Tools for a Global Program, Nov 11, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Strengthening Fragile Families Initiative -- Information and Reports, 1999-2001 (Box 1)
  - Survey of Regional Initiatives in Asia in the Field of Human Rights, Aug 1999 (Box 1)
  - Beyond Borders, Oct 9-14, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Reproductive Health 2000 (Box 1)
  - Strengthening Fragile Families Initiative Close-out Report, Jun 13, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Strengthening Fragile Families Initiative -- Final Report on Work of 14 Grantees, Sep 30, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Working with the Asset Building Framework, Feb 5, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Background Paper on Reproductive Health -- Kenya (Box 1)
  - Strengthening Fragile Families Initiative, n.d. (Box 1)
  - The Ford Foundation in the Philippines (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation China Office Publications (Box 1)
- Meetings, 1995-2001; II
  - Reproductive Health and Population Worldwide Meeting, May 14-19, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Human Development and Reproductive Health Initial Staff Meeting, Oct 17, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Human Development and Reproductive Health Meeting with Grantees on 5-year Review, Mar 27-Apr 15, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Sistersong Conference [PHOTOS], Sep 1998 (Box 2)
  - Human Development Program Review -- Draft, Sep 15, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Reproductive Health Affinity Group Meeting, Nov 7-10, 1998 (Box 2)
  - ASSETS Directors/VP Meeting, Sep 21, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Strengthening Fragile Families Initiative Quarterly Grantee Meeting, Mar 1, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Reproductive Health Affinity Group Meeting, Jun 7, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Beijing +5 Photographs and Background Information [PHOTOS], Jun 8, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Beijing +5 Reports, Jun 8, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Reproductive Health -- Field -- HIV/AIDS Roundtable -- Vietnam, 2001 (Box 2)
  - PCI Screening -- Ford Foundation Level B Auditorium, Apr 5, 2001 (Box 2)
  - International AIDS Issues, May 4, 2001 (Box 2)
  - International Funders Meeting, May 14-15, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Ford Foundation Board of Trustees Meeting, May 23-25, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Leadership Forum on HIV Prevention, Jun 22, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Healthy Wealthy Wise Meeting, Oct 28-30, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Ford Foundation Board of Trustees Meeting, May 21-22, 2002 (Box 2)
- Subject Files, 1984-2002; III
  - Arts Subgroup, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - Big Bet -- Sexuality -- Review, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Big Bet -- Sexuality, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Big Bet -- Sexuality -- Roundtables -- Staff Meetings, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Capacity Building Assistance Teams, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Community and Resource Development Administration, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Culture and Religion Sub-Group, 1994-1996 (Box 3)
  - Hempel, Margaret -- Handover Notebook, 1987-1999 (Box 3)
  - Hempel, Margaret -- Handover Notes, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Hempel/Muecke -- Old Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Human Development and Reproductive Health -- Program Officer Memoranda, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Human Development and Reproductive Health, 1998-2000 (Box 3)
  - Human Development and Reproductive Health -- Material from Muecke, Margorie, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Human Development and Reproductive Health -- Children, Youth and Families, 1999-2001 (Box 3)
  - Human Development and Reproductive Health -- Sexual Health and Well-Being, 2002 (Box 3)
  - International AIDS Presentation -- Durban, 1999 (Box 3)
  - (IWHC) International Women's Health Coalition -- Sexuality and Reproductive Health, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Mature CDC Initiative, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Media Subgroup, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Exit Memorandum, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment A -- Program Officer Memorandum, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment B -- Community Youth Development Initiative Component I, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment C -- Community Youth Development Initiative Component II, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment D -- Youth Leadership for Development Initiative, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment E -- Youth Development Communique, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment F -- Exhange Reports -- Kenya, Nigeria, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment G -- Most Recent DOL/OOP Update, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment H -- CARTA's Workplan and Service Agreement, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment I -- History of Foundations Work in Youth Development, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment J -- Grantee List, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Mohomad, Inca A. -- Exit Memo -- Attachment K -- Miscellaneous Materials on Youth Development, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Population Communication Africa, Feb 2001 (Box 4)
  - (RHAG) Reproductive Health Affinity Group, 1998-2000 (Box 4)
  - (RHAG) Reproductive Health Affinity Group -- General, 1999-2001 (Box 4)
  - Sistersong -- Consultants, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Teenage Pregnancy, 1984-1998 (Box 4)